[Music]
welcome the busy Central lunch event and
our session about payment practices
analyzes in a busy centrer where my
colleague Vadim and I will try to
explain how to use this feature and
where it is applicable I will start
first with a short introduction and
continue with specifics required by some
countries where it can be used as a
regular regulatory feature and then my
colleague V will show you different
models of usage of this new analyes for
payments to vendors and from
customers okay let's start um let's
first explain what payment times or
payment practices analyzes is uh we
simply want to analyze how you behave
against your vent when it comes to the
payments on or after due dates but also
how your customers behave against your
company you can collect this information
on other places but not so
structural additionally some countries
require payment analyes for your vendors
as a regulatory obligation for example
each year Swedish companies with 250 and
more employees must report Swedish
companies registration office that
payment times they have for purchase is
from a company that are smaller than
themselves similar acts exist in United
Kingdom Australia and New Zealand but in
these countries this is not related to
the company size
so we decided to create this app as a
global feature for this kind of
reporting as it can be useful in other
countries as for some additional
analyzis it can become obligatory in
other countries but also can be useful
for internal analyzis or for audit
reporting
and as we had a similar feature earlier
in United Kingdom Bas app we decided to
obsolute this code and deize it
extending this functionality with
additional features so it can work as a
global app so result is a new app but
also one additional step toward the
localization what can we analyze with
this new feature my colleague vadin will
show it in details but I just want to
provide some high level over you users
can choose between two different
aggregation types per period or per
company size per company size is
required in Sweden but in other
countries he mentioned it is required to
provide analyzis per
period now so far authorities require
this analysis work for vendors only but
we decided to extend the feature so you
can use for additional analyzis and now
you can choose between vendors customers
or both of them and
when you aggregate report you can get
detailed lines but also some good
statistics average agreed and actual
payment period and percentage paid on
time now my colleague vadin will show
you first analyzes per company size and
after that per payment times Bim thanks
Alexander uh let me show you how this
works in business Central so uh we will
navigate to the P practices page where
will create a new payment practice
header here we have the options that we
need to uh consider let's start with the
company SE so for this uh we will use a
full year of
24 um and we will fill in all the
necessary uh data after that you just
need to click
generate and the line will be generated
so the data will be collected the header
will be populated with the statistics
such as averages and uh particulars are
generated where you can see
uh uh the statistics for each uh company
size so for company size small for
example you can see uh average GD
payment period and average actual
payment period with the percent p in
time if you're interested in the
particulars uh you can always click uh
on the numbers where you will see the
particular details such as uh what was
the invoice entry what was the payment
entry relating to that invoice and all
the dates uh also the invoice amount Etc
uh this will be the particulars for only
for this line but if you want uh to see
the particular spot all the header you
can click uh on the headers number here
you will see more lines uh all of them
that were used for for this
header uh this data is stored for
historical purposes so you can always
come back and see the historical data so
we did this for the company size uh now
let's uh switch it out oh yeah I forgot
you can also print it so of course when
you need reported you will print it and
uh the appropriate layout will be
selected
Etc let's close this
one yes so now we can go back and
generate one for
period uh one thing to mention about the
company sizes of course you specify the
company sizes uh on the vendor cards and
the ones that are specified will be
included in this
report now let's switch to the uh
aggregation type period you can see the
lines have disappeared because the
aggregation type has changed and they
are no longer valid uh let's regenerate
them
so here we can see the report uh has
generated other lines uh now these are
lines uh that are uh related to the
periods uh those periods are set up in
special table payment periods where you
can specify any periods you desire to
see in this report but for demonstration
purposes uh here here are some lines so
again as uh with company sizes you can
uh drill down into the particulars of
each period where you can see which uh
payments were included why uh some data
on the actual payment days GRE payment
days
Etc um uh one thing to note that in some
countries uh they're more interested uh
in what amounts from invoices were paid
in particular periods and and not the
count of the invoices so this this would
uh be reflected in this statistic so as
we can see here a lot of the invoices
were paid uh very fast but amount wise
they were not even the 1/3 uh and the
bigger invoices are always paid late so
this is something we can learn from this
one also this uh is applicable for
example for we did just did this for
customer but we can do the same for uh
we just did this for we do the same for
customers uh and um yeah this is how you
can use the payment uh practices in your
business Central now take it away
Alexandra thank you Vadim on such a good
presentation and now we are finishing uh
as I like to say this is small feature
but very cool and yeah I want to thank
you all of you uh for attending this
session uh I want to remind you we will
have Q&A session so you can go there you
can ask whatever you want to hear about
this feature if something is missing if
you want to get more information and
before I close this session I want to
invite you I want to invite you to watch
all sessions on BC lunch event of course
but this one what is new legislation
localization is Clos connected with um
what we presented today so it will be
good to to take this session to see all
new things in legislation localization
scope and before I close uh if you need
some information about be Central
whatever topic is you can easily find
one of these links if you cannot
remember all of them minimum try to not
to forget these in the middle AK msbc
all so when you go there you can find
all important information all links
about V Central so once more thank you
for attending this
session